Guide to the Henri Chopin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henri Chopin papers
1948-2009
1960-2007
GEN MSS 868
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.13
(89 boxes) + 9 record album storage, 31 broadside, 5 art.
The Henri Chopin Papers document the work and life of French avant-garde poet and musician Henri Chopin. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, subject files, writings relating to various publications, artwork, writings of others, photographs, audiovisual materials, and posters spanning the years 1948 to 2009.
Chopin, Henri, 1922-2008
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from John Benjamins Antiquariat b.v. and Philippe Luiggi on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 37-53 and 72 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 54-71 and 73-80 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 81 and 122 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Language(s)
In French and English.
Henri Chopin (1922-2008)
Henri Chopin, primarily a French avant-garde poet and musician, but also a painter, graphic artist and designer, typographer, independent publisher, and filmmaker. He was born in Paris on June 18, 1922 and died in Dereham, England on January 3, 2008.
Chopin was a French practitioner of concrete and sound poetry and created recordings using tape recorders, various studio technologies, and the sounds of the human voice. Chopin's published works include the books Le Dernier Roman du Monde (1971), Portrait des 9 (1975), The Cosmographical Lobster (1976), Poésie Sonore Internationale (1979), Les Riches Heures de l'Alphabet (1992) and Graphpoemesmachine (2006); the magazines Cinquième Saison and OU (1958-1974); and typewriter poems, also known as dactylopoèmes.
Scope and Contents
The Henri Chopin Papers document the work and life of French avant-garde poet and musician Henri Chopin. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, subject files, writings relating to various publications, artwork, writings of others, photographs, audiovisual materials, and posters spanning the years 1948 to 2009.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1960-2004. II. Cinquième Saison and OU Files 1960-2009. III. Artwork, 1967-2006. IV. Works by Others, 1948-2006.V. Photographs, circa 1960-2000. VI. Writings, 1952-2007. VII. Audiovisual Material, 1957-2007. VIII. Posters, 1967-2006. IX. September 2013 Acquisition, 1963-2007.
Artists, France -- 20th Century; Concrete poetry, French -- 20th Century; Design -- 20th Century; French poetry -- 20th Century; Graphic arts -- 20th Century; Musicians -- France -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, French -- 20th Century -- Archives; Publishing -- 20th Century; Sound poetry, French -- 20th Century; Printing; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Posters; Realia; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Musicians -- France -- 20th Century; Poets -- France -- 20th Century; Chopin, Henri, 1922-2008
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1960-2004; Series I; 6; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The first run of correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The second run of correspondence is arranged by the correspondents' country of origin and other subjects. Filed at the end of the series is various correspondence not included with the others.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of files of correspondence and other material shedding light on Chopin's development as an artist.
  - "A" General, 1978-1993, undated (Box 1)
  - Aquaviva, Frédéric, 2001-2007, undated (Box 1)
  - Albert-Birot, Arlette, 1969-2000, undated (Box 1)
  - Anseeuw, Alain, 1973, undated (Box 1)
  - "B" General, 1972-2008, undated (Box 1)
  - Buhler, Rosine, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
  - Bedou, Dominique, 1979 February- July (Box 1)
  - Bekri, Tahar, 1993, undated (Box 1)
  - Benhamou, Maurice, 1977-1985 (Box 1)
  - Blank, Jeremy, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bobillot, Jean-Pierre, 1995, undated (Box 1)
  - Boussand, Juliette, 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - Brindeau, Serge & Paule, 1974-1986 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Jean, 1972-1986 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Paul, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Bulatov, Dmitry, undated (Box 1)
  - "C" General, 1975-2008, undated (Box 1)
  - Cernotto, Andrea, 1992-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Charbonnier, Georges, 1973-1988, undated (Box 1)
  - Charette, Marin de, 2003-2004, undated (Box 1)
  - "D" General, 1974-2007, undated (Box 1)
  - De Smet, Bernard, 1969, undated (Box 1)
  - "E" General, 1978-2005 (Box 1)
  - "F" General, 1984-2007, undated (Box 1)
  - "G" General, 1968-2004, undated (Box 1)
  - Gentils, René, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Gherban, Alexandre, 1989-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - "H" General, 1976-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Herrero-Ducloux, Abel, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Hetten, Claude, 1983-1993, undated (Box 1)
  - Hubert, Judd & Renée Riese, 1993-2002, undated (Box 1)
  - Hudak, John, 1987-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - "J" General, 1982-2004 (Box 2)
  - Jandl, Ernst, 1977-1981 (Box 2)
  - Jani, Sylvie, 1985-1989 (Box 2)
  - Jegou, Alain, 2005-2007 (Box 2)
  - "K" General, 1972-2004, undated (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Carole, 1993-2007 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Douglas, 1988, undated (Box 2)
  - Kelter, Christina, 1996-2002 (Box 2)
  - Kolodny, Frank, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - "L" General, 1967-1992, undated (Box 2)
  - Leclerc, Daniel, 1997-2005 (Box 2)
  - Linhartová, Věra, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Lurie, Toby, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - "M" General, 1972-2002, undated (Box 2)
  - Mairey, Françoise, 1975, undated (Box 2)
  - McAlpine, Alistair, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
    Includes photocopies of letters from Henri Chopin to Raoul Hausman, 1963-1971
  - Mercher-Brousse, Henri, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Métail, Michèle, 1975-2006, undated (Box 2)
  - Miskin, Lionel, 1967, undated (Box 2)
  - "N" General, 1991-1996, undated (Box 2)
  - Nadau, Jean-Pierre, undated (Box 2)
  - Nakov, Andrei Boris, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2)
  - Nordin, Ingvar Loco, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Nuaud, Jean-Pierre, 1993-1995, undated (Box 2)
  - "O" General, 1972-1992, undated (Box 2)
  - "P" General, 1972-2000, undated (Box 2)
  - Palermo, Fiorenzo, 2006 February-September (Box 2)
  - Pestana, Silvestre, 1979-1982, undated (Box 2)
  - Peynaud, Claude, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - Plantier, Thérèse, 1971-1987 (Box 2)
  - Power, Kevin C., undated (Box 2)
  - Prévot, Marthe, 1972-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - "R" General, 1972-2003, undated (Box 2)
  - Rushton, Anthony P., undated (Box 2)
  - "S" General, 1973-2001, undated (Box 2)
  - Scholz, Christian, 1973-1995 (Box 2)
  - Sorin, Raphaël, 1973-1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Sulzbach, Renée, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
  - "T" General, 1969-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - Trouvé, Henri, 1974-1987, undated (Box 3)
  - Trowell, Stephen G., 1974-2000, undated (Box 3)
  - "U" General, 1973-1978 (Box 3)
  - "V" General, 1968-1992 (Box 3)
  - Vince, John, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - "W" General, 1968-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - "Z" General, 1976-1992 (Box 3)
  - Zweig, Ellen, 1983-1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Students, 1990-2002, undated (Box 3)
  - United Kingdom
    - Cities & Universities, circa 1969-2004 (Box 3)
    - Festival Ingatestone, 1969 (Box 3)
    - University of Manchester, 1972-1977 (Box 3)
    - O'Connor, Michael, 1974, undated (Box 3)
    - Galleries & Publishers, circa 1969-2004 (Box 3)
    - Gaberbocchus Press Limited, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1972-1978 (Box 3)
    - The Birmingham Arts Laboratory Ltd., 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Eastern Arts Association, 1972-1979, undated (Box 3)
    - Ilkley Literature Festival, 1978-1979, undated (Box 3)
    - Carrell, Christofer, 1970-1984 (Box 3)
    - Finch, Peter, 1975-1979, undated (Box 3)
    - Furnival, John & Astrid, 1983-2006, undated (Box 3)
    - Leonard, Tom & Hughson, Joan, 1977-1987, undated (Box 3)
    - Reichardt, Jasia, 1965-1999, undated (Box 4)
    - Richardson, Robert, 1979-2003, undated (Box 4)
    - Tabor, Richard, 1973-1993, undated (Box 4)
    - Vonna-Michell, Erik, 1979-1990, undated (Box 4)
  - Italy
    - Cities & Universities, 1967-1994, undated (Box 4)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-1993, undated (Box 4)
    - Bellora, Gianfranco, 1975-1987, undated (Box 4)
    - Bertola, Carla & Vitacchio, Alberto, 1987-2004, undated (Box 4)
    - Bertozzi, Gabriele-Aldo, 1988-1993 (Box 4)
    - Bonotto, Luigi, 1992-2006 (Box 4)
    - Caignard, Rolland, 1996-2003 (Box 4)
    - Carcano, Emanuele, 1995-1998, undated (Box 4)
    - Conz, Francesco, 1968-2007, undated (Box 4)
    - Fontana, Giovanni, 1980-2007, undated (Box 4)
    - Nannucci, Mauritio, 1967-1995 (Box 4)
    - Minarelli, Enzo, 1982-2004, undated (Box 4)
    - Morghen, Gianni, 2007, undated (Box 4)
    - Studio Morra, 1979-2006, undated (Box 4)
    - Sarenco, 1972-1996, undated (Box 4)
    - Schwarz, Arturo, 1976-1979 (Box 5)
  - Belgium
    - Cities & Universities, 1963-1998 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1979-2003, undated (Box 5)
    - Atelier de Création Sonore Radiophonique, 2003-2004, undated (Box 5)
    - Instituut voor Psychoacustica en Elektronische Muziek, Gent, 1976-1991 (Box 5)
    - MAC's Grand-Hornu, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Dachy, Marc, 1973-1977 (Box 5)
    - Edeline, François, 1972-2007 (Box 5)
    - De Maere, Jan, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
    - Schraenen, Guy, 1973-1994 (Box 5)
    - Sotiaux, Daniel, 1979-1989 (Box 5)
    - Van der Hoeven, Jan, 1981-1984 (Box 5)
  - United States of America
    - Cities & Universities, 1972-2005 (Box 5)
    - White, Erdmute Wenzel, 1972-1985 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1965-1993, undated (Box 5)
    - Kostelanets, Richard, 1976-1985 (Box 5)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1978-1996 (Box 5)
    - The Ruth & Marvin Sackner Archive, 1971-2005 (Box 5)
  - Canada
    - Cities & Universities, 1974-2006, undated (Box 5)
    - The 11th International Festival of Sound Poetry, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Le Lieu: Centre en Art Actuel, 1986-2007 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1973-1978 (Box 5)
    - Beaulieu, Simone, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Vie Des Arts, 1968-1980 (Box 6)
  - Austria
    - Cities & Universities, 1983-1995
    - Schule für Dichtung in Wien, 1985-2007 (Box 6)
    - Jaschke, Gerhard, 1984-1991 (Box 6)
  - Switzerland
    - Cities & Universities, 1973-2003 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, circa 1979-1992 (Box 6)
    - Aaron, Richard, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Adler, Marcel, 1972-1979 (Box 6)
    - Armleder, John M., 1973-1977 (Box 6)
    - Barras, Vincent, 1988-2005 (Box 6)
    - Lagarde, François, 1975-1985 (Box 6)
  - Sweden
    - Swedish Embassy, London, 1978 December 12 (Box 6)
    - Centre Culturel Suédois, 1979-1991 (Box 6)
    - Malmö Konsthall, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - Fylkingen, 1969-1977 (Box 6)
  - The Netherlands
    - Cities & Universities, 1968-1993 (Box 6)
    - Landy, Leigh, 1981-1993 (Box 6)
    - Stedelijk Museum, 1974-1985 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-2007 (Box 6)
    - Ruhé, Harry, 1980-1984 (Box 6)
    - Van Toorn, Jan, 1980-2000 (Box 6)
    - De Waard, Frans, 1994-1997 (Box 6)
  - Germany
    - Cities & Universities, 1989-1995, undated (Box 6)
    - Literaturwerkstatt Berlin, 2003 (Box 6)
    - Bielefelder Colloquium Neue Poesie, 1985-1995 (Box 6)
    - Universität Gesamthochschule Siegen, 1981-1992 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-2006, undated (Box 6)
    - Archiv Sohm, 1969-1983 (Box 6)
    - Breger, Udo, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Dana, Llys, 1994-2007 (Box 6)
    - Hundertmark, Armin, 1975-2002 (Box 7)
    - S Press Tonbandverlag, 1973-1997 (Box 7)
  - South America
    - Cities & Universities, 1973-1993 (Box 7)
  - Australia
    - Cities & Universities, 1969-1992 (Box 7)
    - Contemporary Sound Arts, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Denmark
    - Cities & Universities, 1978-1984 (Box 7)
  - Spain
    - Cities & Universities, 1975-1997 (Box 7)
    - Galeria Sephira, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Cinca, Javier, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - Greece
    - Cities & Universities, 1987-1991 (Box 7)
  - Israel
    - Shelef, Zvi, 1987 May-June (Box 7)
  - Japan
    - Kouhei & Akiko, 2004-2005 (Box 7)
    - Shimoda, Seiji, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Poland
    - Cities & Universities, 1978-1986 (Box 7)
    - The International Drawing Triennial, Wrocław, 1978-1982 (Box 7)
    - Kostołowski, Andrzej, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
    - Galeria Akumulatory 2, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Portugal
    - Cities & Universities, 1976-1996 (Box 7)
  - Czech Republic
    - Cities & Universities, 1967-1998 (Box 7)
    - Bienále Užité Grafiky, Brno, 1969-1974 (Box 7)
    - Dilia, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - TV - Radio - Magazines
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1968-1988 (Box 7)
    - Saarländischer Rundfunk, 1976 March 4 (Box 7)
    - Telefilm Saar GmbH, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Westdeutscher Rundfunk, 1972-1997 (Box 7)
    - Esser, Nina, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
    - Lenz, Michael, 1996 (Box 7)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1968-1984 (Box 7)
    - Australian Broadcasting Coproration, 1983-1997 (Box 7)
    - Radiodiffusion-Télévision Belge, undated (Box 7)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1968-1995 (Box 7)
    - Magazines, 1976-2001 (Box 7)
    - Radio France, 1977-1995 (Box 7)
    - France Culture, 1980-1993 (Box 7)
    - Encyclopaedia Universalis, 1988-1995 (Box 7)
    - Sveriges Radio, 1969-1989 (Box 7)
    - Sveriges Riksradio AB, 1991-1994 (Box 7)
    - Télévision Suisse Romande, 1963-1975 (Box 7)
    - Radio Lausanne, 1963 November 26 (Box 8)
    - KCMU, Seattle, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
    - KPFA, Berkeley, 1972-1983 (Box 8)
  - Press releases, circa 1961-1963 (Box 8)
  - France
    - Officials, 1977-1993 (Box 8)
    - Actions pour Promouvoir le Français des Affaires, 1991-2005 (Box 8)
    - Société des Gens de Lettres de France, 1976-1988 (Box 8)
    - Société Civile des Auteurs Multimedia, 1982-2004 (Box 8)
    - Monnaie de Paris, 1986-2000 (Box 8)
    - Ministère de L'Education Nationale et de la Culture, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
    - Présidence de la Republique, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
    - Ministère de la Culture, 1964-1996 (Box 8)
    - Centre national des arts plastiques, 1985 June 28 (Box 8)
    - Bibliothèque nationale de France, 1989-2006 (Box 8)
    - Cabinet des Estampes, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
    - Imprimerie nationale, 1989 May-June (Box 8)
    - Estampes et photos, 1990-2003 (Box 8)
    - Centre Georges Pompidou, 1974-2001 (Box 8)
    - Institut de Recherche et Coordination Acoustique/Musique, 1994, undated (Box 8)
    - Cities & Universities, 1995-2000 (Box 8)
    - Bioulès, Vincent, 1981-1994 (Box 9)
    - Bibliothèque Municipale, Amiens, 1991-1993 (Box 9)
    - Bourges, 1979-1994 (Box 9)
    - Ville de Clermont Ferrand, 1995-1997 (Box 9)
    - Grenoble, 1996-2004 (Box 9)
    - Maison de la Culture du Havre, 1975-1980 (Box 9)
    - Université de Nantes, 1985-1992 (Box 9)
    - Ville de Nîmes, 1980-1982 (Box 9)
    - Musées de Marseilles, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Festival Expoésie, Périgueux, 2005-2006 (Box 9)
    - Toulouse, 1982-2001 (Box 9)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1989-2006 (Box 9)
    - Arnaudet, Didier, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Barrière, Françoise, 1975-2005 (Box 9)
    - Galerie Convergence, Nantes, 1987-2000 (Box 9)
    - Beurard, Patrick, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - Collet, Michel & Verhaeghe, Valentine, 1995-2006 (Box 9)
    - Duchêne, Gérard, 1977-1994, undated (Box 9)
    - Ensemble Vide, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
    - Féray, Marie-Laure & Serge, 1993-2008, undated (Box 9)
    - Tartalacrème, 1980-1992 (Box 9)
    - Librairie-galerie sel du marchand, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
    - Hubaut, Joël, 1987-1997, undated (Box 9)
    - Hurtado, Eric & Marc, 1995 January 25 (Box 9)
    - Malartre, André, 1991-1993 (Box 9)
    - Mathieu, Didier, 1991-2006 (Box 9)
    - Meier, Richard, 1989-2005, undated (Box 9)
    - Montessuis, Joachim, 1994-2005 (Box 9)
    - Metamkine, 1995-2003 (Box 9)
    - Tyson, Matthew, 1984-1995, undated (Box 9)
    - Schwartz, Paul, 1981-1994, undated (Box 9)
    - Foundation Danae, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Paris
    - Publishers & Galleries, 1979-2006 (Box 10)
    - Lucken, Christopher, 1996-1998, undated (Box 10)
    - Debon, Claude, 1994 July-November (Box 10)
    - Galleries & Booksellers, 1971-1995, undated (Box 10)
    - Publishers, 1967-2001, undated (Box 10)
    - Bory, Jean-François, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
    - Canorel, Franck, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Delaunay, Philippe, 2006-2007 (Box 10)
    - Dufeu, Antoine, 2003-2007 (Box 10)
    - Giroud, Michel, 1975-1987 (Box 10)
    - Lebel, Jean-Jacques, 1979-1990, undated (Box 10)
    - Lemaire, Gérard-Georges, 1975-1993, undated (Box 10)
    - Orta, Jorge, 1998-2000 (Box 10)
    - Place, Jean-Michel, 1976-2007, undated (Box 10)
    - Petithory, Jean & Chantal, 1972-1989, undated (Box 10)
    - Restany, Pierre, 1976, undated (Box 10)
    - Roulet, Jean-Claude, 1982-1992 (Box 10)
    - Sabaté Bériain, Hélios, 1981-2006 (Box 10)
    - Saillard, Martine, 1998-2005 (Box 10)
    - Sauvagnac, Nicole, 1980-1985, undated (Box 10)
    - Vernier, Marc, 2001-2006 (Box 10)
  - Artists
    - Aeschbacher, Arthur, 1977-1983 (Box 10)
    - Aguirre, Javier, 1969-1982 (Box 10)
    - Arp, Jean & Marguerite, 1964 March-May (Box 10)
    - Arcand, Pierre-André, 1989-2002, undated (Box 10)
    - Autrand, Charles, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
    - Ball, Hugo, 1976 July 25 (Box 10)
    - Grögerová, Bohumila & Hiršal, Josef, 1965-1990, undated (Box 11)
    - Balpe, Jean-Pierre, 1976-1994 (Box 11)
    - Battier, Marc, 1984-1993, undated (Box 11)
    - Bergner, Marcus, 1993, undated (Box 11)
    - Bosseur, Jean-Yves, 1977-1984 (Box 11)
    - Boussand, Marcel, 1971-1995, undated (Box 11)
    - Brunson, Bill, 1975-1977 (Box 11)
    - Burke, Herbert, 1974-1984 (Box 11)
    - Cage, John, 1984 September 25 (Box 11)
    - Crozier, Robin, 1971 October-November (Box 11)
    - Curtay, Jean-Paul, circa 1979-1989 (Box 11)
    - Darras, Jacques, 1982-1996 (Box 11)
    - Donguy, Jacques, 1986-2007 (Box 11)
    - Dutton, Paul, 1983-2002 (Box 11)
    - Ferrando, Bartolomé, 1991-2002, undated (Box 11)
    - Godard, Maxime, 1993 May-July (Box 11)
    - Gonçalves, Olga, 1976 January-February, undated (Box 11)
    - Greenham, Lily, 1978-1979, undated (Box 11)
    - Gruber, Jacques, 1973, undated (Box 11)
    - Henry, Maurice, 1969 June 5 (Box 11)
    - Herel, Petr, 1983-1999, undated (Box 11)
    - Higgins, Dick, 1975-1997, undated (Box 11)
    - Hublin, Serge, 1978 May-July (Box 11)
    - Jappe, Elisabeth, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - Kaplan, Philip, 1969-1985, undated (Box 11)
    - Kemp, Penny, undated (Box 11)
    - Kern, Bliem W., 1977-1981 (Box 11)
    - Keppler, Joseph, 1983-1990, undated (Box 11)
    - Kroupa, Adolf, 1969-1973 (Box 11)
    - Kucharz, Lawrence, 1978-1979, undated (Box 11)
    - Lafabrie, Bernard-Gabriel, 1991-1992, undated (Box 11)
    - Laszlo, Jean-Noël, 1989-2007 (Box 11)
    - Latal, Georges, 1969-1990 (Box 11)
    - Artists, 1971-1999, undated (Box 12)
    - Mallin, Rupert, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Mikriammos, Philippe, 1975-1977 (Box 12)
    - Miller, David, 1975-1977 (Box 12)
    - Miranda, Fatima, 1993-2006, undated (Box 12)
    - Mon, Franz, 1976-1981 (Box 12)
    - Noël, Christophe, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
    - Özkök, Lütfi, 1970-1993, undated (Box 12)
    - Parant, Jean-Luc, 1987-2005 (Box 12)
    - Pénard, Rémy, 1993-2004 (Box 12)
    - Pétronio, Arthur, 1976-1979, undated (Box 12)
    - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard), 1964-1977, undated (Box 12)
    - Pisek, Bruno, 1995-2005 (Box 12)
    - Pont, Gérard, 1983 March-October (Box 12)
    - Pooley, Hugh, 1975-1976, undated (Box 12)
    - Popper, Frank, 1968-1982 (Box 12)
    - Proïa, François, 1990-1993, undated (Box 12)
    - Raïna, 1977, undated (Box 12)
    - Ramos, Jose Miguel, 1974-1976, undated (Box 12)
    - Restany, Pierre, 1986-1990 (Box 12)
    - Richter, Hans, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
    - Rougier, Vincent, 1989-2005, undated (Box 12)
    - Roussel, Alain, undated (Box 12)
    - Rühm, Gerhard, 1981-1987 (Box 12)
    - Ruppenthal, Steve, 1972-1979, undated (Box 12)
    - Saint Helm, 1960-1985 (Box 12)
    - Scherstjanoi, Valerie, 1991-2003 (Box 12)
    - Smadja, Alex, undated (Box 12)
    - Sondzia, Joseph, 1971-1979 (Box 12)
    - Strange, Allen, 1978-1980, undated (Box 12)
    - Viallat, 1981 January-February (Box 12)
    - De Vree, Freddy, 1978, undated (Box 12)
    - Wendt, Larry, 1978-2003 (Box 12)
    - Williams, Emmett, 1987 January-May (Box 12)
    - Wilmański, Tomasz, 1986-1991, undated (Box 12)
    - Xenakis, Constantin, undated (Box 12)
    - Yterce, Alexandre, 1998-2002 (Box 13)
    - Zumthor, Paul, 1979-1994, undated (Box 13)
  - Exhibitions, circa 1964-2007; 3 (Box 13)
  - Invitations, circa 1956-2004; 3 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1961-1978 (Box 13)
  - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1969-2000; 3 (Box 13)
  - Solt, Mary Ellen, 1968-1972, undated (Box 13)
  - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1965-2002; 4 (Box 13)
  - Bertini, Gianni, 1969, undated (Box 13)
  - Autograph letter signed from [undeciphered] & Gianni Bertini to Brigitte Chopin, 2008 March 7 (Box 13)
  - Note from Pierre Albert-Birot to Henri Chopin, 1986 May 13 (Box 13)
  - Note from Duncan Bush to Henri Chopin & Jean Ratcliffe-Chopin, undated (Box 13)
  - Note from Dmitri Bulatov to Henri Chopin, undated (Box 13)
  - Typescript letter signed from Henri Chopin to Gianni Bertini, 1971 December 25 (Box 13)
  - Autograph letter signed from Alan Riddell to Henri Chopin, undated (Box 13)
  - Note from Carlfriedrich Claus to Henri Chopin, 1991 June 13 (Box 13)
  - Chopin, Henri: La voix, typescript, undated (Box 13)
  - Autograph letter signed from Michel Seuphor to Jean Ratcliffe-Chopin, 1966 November 11 (Box 13)
  - Autograph letter signed from Jean-Paul Curtay to Henri Chopin, 1979 October 10 (Box 13)
  - Typescript letter signed from Johanna Ricard to Henri Chopin, 1976 June 10 (Box 13)
  - Autograph letter signed from Régine Chopinot to Henri Chopin, 2007 November 22 (Box 13)
  - Chopin, Henri. La ville couvre toute la nature, typescript, 1965 January (Box 13)
  - Typescript letter signed from J.C. Pellegry to Henri Chopin, 1985 March 5 (Box 13)
  - Two photographs, undated (Box 13)
  - Typescript letter signed from Sarenco and Anna to Henri Chopin, 1985 January 15 (Box 13)
  - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1964-2000; 2 (Box 13)
- Cinquième Saison and OU Files, 1960-2009; Series II; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  Series II consists of files relating to Chopin's work on the magazines Cinquième Saison and OU. Files include correspondence with various collaborators and contributors, projects descriptions, purchase orders, grant applications, and other papers.
  - Cinquième Saison Files
    - Syte, Raymond, 1979-1988, undated (Box 13)
    - Project description, undated (Box 13)
    - Purchase orders, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
    - Grant applications, 1962-1965, undated (Box 13)
    - Declarations of publication, circa 1960-1967 (Box 13)
  - Bekaert, Jacques, 1976-2000, undated (Box 14)
  - Burka, Jean, 1978 February 28 (Box 14)
  - OU Files
    - Purchases, 1967-1978 (Box 14)
    - Suppliers, 1965-2007 (Box 14)
    - Marcourel, Jean, 1989-2004 (Box 14)
    - Hughes, Patrick, 1975, undated (Box 14)
    - Artwork, poems, and printed material, 1966, undated (Box 14)
    - Albert-Birot, Pierre, 1964-1966 (Box 14)
    - Altman, Robert, circa 1967-1992 (Box 14)
    - Altmann, Roberto, 1964-1973 (Box 14)
    - Apeiros, 1974 January-June (Box 14)
    - Centre d'Art et de Communication, 1974-1978, undated (Box 14)
    - Arnaud, Noël, 1964-1993, undated (Box 14)
    - Aubertin, Bernard, 1968-1995, undated (Box 14)
    - Béguier, Serge, 1971 March 8 (Box 14)
    - Vautier, Ben, 1965-1972, undated (Box 14)
    - Berni, Antonio, 1964-1972 (Box 14)
    - Bertini, Gianni, 1965-2009, undated (Box 14)